准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
邻家藻分外青
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
不好意思  小姐
Pardon me, young lady
她好漂亮
What a fox
调料区
你要归我了  可爱的蟹黄堡
You're all mine, you sweet Krabby Patty
启动发射程序
Initiating launch sequence
蟹黄堡  我来了
Krabby Patty, here I come
希望这次别又射偏了
I hope I don't miss again
重聚的感觉真美妙
Reunited, and it's going to feel so good
蟹老板
可爱的钱
Sweet wampum
什么东西
What's that?
章鱼哥  你在哪
Squidward, where are you?
用你的额头保护我
Shield me with your forehead
所以
So
是竞争对手痞老板又没偷到蟹黄堡
it was just another failed Krabby Patty theft attempt
by my arch-competitor, Plankton
我原先差点还把你当成威胁了
For a second there, I mistook you for a threat
然而你就只是个肮脏的卑鄙小人
but you're just a dirty, little man
再见了  小虾米
So long, shrimp
我诅咒你  蟹老板
Curse you, Mr. Krabs
海之霸
看得出来今天又失败了  对吧亲爱的
So, typical day of failure, I see, huh, darling?
别说了  电脑老婆
Can it, computer wife
你就看不出来我累坏了吗
Can't you see I'm exhausted?
怎么不去做点有用的事
Why don't you go make yourself useful
给我合成点吃的
and synthesize me up some grub?
遵命  陛下
Yes, Your Majesty
看看有什么吃的
What do we got here?
好啊
Goodie
又是全息肉糕
Holographic meatloaf again
我什么时候才能吃得到真正的食物
When am I going to get some real food?
蟹老板就吃得到真正的食物
Mr. Krabs gets to eat real food
看他女儿
Just look at his daughter
块头跟鲸鱼一样大
She's as big as a whale
希望我能跟蟹老板一样成功
I wish I could be successful like Mr. Krabs
希望我可以用某种办法跟他交换身份
I wish I could somehow just switch lives with him
知道他的大号生活是什么样
just to know what it's like
那要不然你就来用一下
Then why don't you just use
那个身份交换了解生活之变身机
that Switch-Lives-Just-to-Know-
What-It's-Like-O-Mogrifier thing
你上周二做的
you built last Tuesday?
真是个好办法
What a brilliant idea
你爸妈先前肯定就是
Your parents must have been, like
半台电脑什么的
part computer or something
来看看
Now, let's see here
不行
No
虽然很不愿意与你分离  凯伦
Well, I hate to leave you, Karen
但要知道俗话说得好
but you know what they say
换身份  来去无牵挂
"a rolling stone gathers no algae"
我的海神王啊
Dear Neptune above
昨晚是怎么了
What happened last night?
这什么东西
What's this?
痞老板
"Mr. Plankton"?
这到底
Who the davey?
我在蟹堡王里了
I'm in the Krusty Krab
这就表示身份交换机
And that means the life switcher
成功了
was a success
蟹堡王归我了
The Krusty Krab is mine
公司休闲装
Corporate casual
上菜了
Order up
两个豪华蟹黄堡
Two deluxe Krabby Patties
终于啊
At last
给你  先生
There you are, sir
两个豪华
Two deluxe
痞老板好
Ahoy, there, Mr. Plankton
你好
Hey, there, uh
海绵宝宝
Spongebob
怎么了  老板
Yes, sir?
我得拿个蟹黄堡
I'm going to need to take one of these patties
回我办公室去
back to my office for, uh
进行抽查
bun inspection
很抱歉不可以  痞老板
I'm afraid you can't do that, Mr. Plankton
为什么
But why not?
因为那个蟹黄堡是给客人吃的  老板
Because that patty is for the customer, sir
客人
The customer?
我要把客人放热油里煮了
I'll boil the customer in hot oil
然后再扒了他
and I'll rip out his
我是说  当然好了
I mean, yes, of course
顾客至上
for the lovely customer
不过你可以拿这俩蟹黄堡  老板
But you can take these patties, sir
我做出来是为了以防万一
I made them on the off chance
为你今天可能决定要做抽查做准备
you decided to instigate some bun inspection today
痞老板先生
Mr. Plankton, sir
没错
Yes
非常好
Very nice
谢谢
Thanks
我的了
All mine
终于是我的了
It's finally all mine
蟹黄堡
The patties
财富
the wealth
坏名声
the notoriety
商务奖
金钱杂志
还有
the
海绵宝宝
Spongebob?
你想干什么
What do you want?
就是  又到星期二了
Well, it's just that it's Tuesday again, sir
不知道我能不能有
and I was wondering if I could have my
有
my, uh
每周绩效评价
weekly performance review
评价
Review?
没错
Oh, yes
拜托了  老板
please, sir, please
可我以前啥都没评价过
But I've never reviewed anything
除了我表亲发给我的外国健身视频
except for those foreign exercise videos
my cousin sent me
拜托了  老板
Oh, please, sir
我想让你高兴又骄傲
I want to make you so happy and proud
你表现还行
You're doing fine
走开  让我自个儿做事
Now leave me to my work
可是老板
But sir
我不是都把你打发走了
I thought I sent you away, Cretan
可是老板
But sir
我一定有哪个方面需要改进
there's got to be something I need to improve on
说什么都行
Anything
好  酱料
All right, the sauce
什
Wh
什么
what?
酱料吧
The sauce, I don't know
你放太多酱料了  总行了吧
You're using too much sauce, okay?
评完了
Review's over
怎么
What?
你怎么了
What's the matter with you?
我只是说酱料有点多了
All I said was a little too much sauce
其实没什么大不了的
It's no big deal, really
你想要我给你什么  升职吗
What do you want from me, a promotion?
升
A pro
a promot
升职
a promotion?
没错  你
Sure, kid, you're, uh
你现在去当收银员
you're on register now
收银员
Register?
真高兴结束了
Glad that's over
海绵宝宝  你还记不记得
Spongebob, do you remember
我们先前怎么讨论私人空间问题的
that little talk we had about personal space?
没关系的  章鱼哥
It's okay, Squidward
我有授权
I'm official
你看
Look
联合收银员
Co-cashier?
你们两个是不是已经认识很久了
So, have you two known each other long?
你不能这么对待我  痞老板
You can't do this to me, Mr. Plankton
要是你真觉得我能一整天站外面
If you think I'm going to stand out there all day
听那个
listening to
那你脑子肯定进珊瑚了
then you must have coral wedged in your frontal lobe
所以你想要我干什么
So what do you want me to do about it?
我想要我的眼前能少一点黄色
I'd like my view to be a little less yellow
懂我的意思吧
if you know what I mean
希望你喜欢灰色
Hope you like gray
章鱼哥  我能从这扇小窗户看到你
Hey, Squidward, I can see you through this little window
别再来打扰了
Now, no more intrusions
我要开始写我成功故事的回忆录了
I'd like to begin writing
the memoirs of my success story
大家就乖乖待在
So everyone just stay the
老爸
Daddy
想要什么就跟你爸直说
Just tell Daddy what you want
老爸
Daddy
他非常忙
He's very busy
我可不可以
Could I please have a, um
提前要一点零花钱吗
an advance on my allowance?
能把你打发走就行
If it'll get you out of my antennae
去嗨吧
Go crazy
才一块钱
One dollar
你不爱我
You hate me
你
You
我吗
Me?
你觉得这好笑吗
You think this is funny?
倒是有那么几分好笑
In a cosmic sort of way, yes
那么  好笑先生
Well, Mr. Funny Man
你的病态乐趣是这么来的吗
is this how you get your sick kicks?
怎么了
What?
不就是个普通的蟹黄
It's just an ordinary Krabby
我的老天
Oh, my goodness
章鱼哥
Squidward
我尽力了  痞老板
I tried, Mr. Plankton
真的尽力了
I really did
又怎么了
What now?
有客人点了中杯汽水
A customer ordered a medium soda
可我却给了大杯
and I gave him a large
我却给了大杯
I gave him a large
我玷污了蟹堡王的好名声
I've soiled the good Krusty Krab name
玷污了
Soiled it
我命令你住口
I command you to stop that
住口  回到你的工作岗位上
Stop that, and return to your post
玷污了
Soiled it
这东西要按哪里才关得掉
Where's the off button on this thing?
好了  爸
Okay, Daddy
我已经决定好离家出走了
I've decided I'm going to run away
出走去认个新爸
Run away and find a new daddy
别说了
Make it stop
怎么了  触发了什么秘密关键词吗
What, did I say the secret word?
不对  老板
No, sir
他回来了
He's back
谁回来了
Who's back?
什么
What?
什么东西
What was that?
驻守阵地
Man your stations
红色警报
Red alert
找掩护
Take cover
躲啥要掩护
Take cover from what?
他就在这附近某处
He's around here somewhere
他过去了
There he goes
什么
What?
是谁
Who?
在哪
Where?
谁来跟我说明下
Somebody tell me
据说他是从最深的海沟爬出来的
Some say he crawled out
from the lowest trench in the ocean
他是水手当中最为粗俗的一个
He's the saltiest of all of the sea dogs
他是裤头村的头号公敌
He's the most hated creature in Bikini Bottom
他最终还是得到了蟹黄堡
And he's finally got a Krabby Patty
老螃蟹
Krabs?
这到底是怎么回事
What the barnacle is going on here?
他是你的死对头
It's your arch-competitor
蟹老板
Krabs
一生中的目标就是要偷到蟹黄堡
His goal in life is to steal a Krabby Patty
毁掉我们的蟹堡王
and ruin our restaurant
太可怕了
That's terrible
没错
Yeah
但是最可怕的地方是
But the worst part of it is
我的天啊  他没穿衣服
Good grief, he's naked
有种就给我穿衣服啊  旱鸭子一群
Clothe me if you can, silly landlubbers
我要让你把话收回去  老螃蟹
I'm going to make you eat those words, Krabs
不穿衣服  不穿鞋
No shirt, no shoes
不提供服务
no service
还是给我穿上了
You got me
不过起码是件内衣
Well, at least it's underwire
臭汉堡还给你们
Here's your stinking patty
这我就不懂了
I don't understand
这里煤气泄露了吗
Is there a gas leak in here?
我的天啊  蟹黄堡回来啦
Knick-knack, the patty's back
你成功了  痞老板
You did it, Mr. Plankton
胜利的尖叫
Victory screech
享受你胜利的尖叫吧  痞老板
Enjoy your victory screech, Plankton
总有一天  蟹黄堡秘方会到我手上
because someday the Krabby Patty formula will be mine
你绝对得不到秘方  大坏蛋
You'll never get this formula you twisted fiend
我会的
But I will
就算我得明天再回来
Even if I have to come back tomorrow
还有再明天
and the next day
找你的电话  痞老板
Phone call, Mr. Plankton
再明天
The next day
还有再明天
and the next day
根本不值得
It's not worth it
一点都不值得
It's just not worth it
大家再见了
Good-bye, everyone
心理治疗期间  我会记得你们的
I'll remember you all in therapy
全息肉糕
Holographic meatloaf
我的最爱
my favorite
救生员
海绵宝宝
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
欢迎来到酷乐湖
啊
Ah
酷乐湖
Goo Lagoon
太阳热着
where the sun is hot
日光浴者则
and the sunbathers are
酷着
so cool
多美好的一天
What a beautiful day
说的没错
You said it, pal
这太阳晒得真舒服阿
Can you believe that sun?
我都能一整天盯着它看
I could look at it all day
派大星
Patrick?
怎么了
What?
没事
Nothing
晒得怎么样了
So, how's that tan coming?
不知道
I don't know
我看下
Let me check
晒得不错
Looking good
你晒得怎么样
How's yours?
等一下啊
Just a minute
我明明记得我是仰面躺着的
I could have sworn I was laying on my back
拉里
Larry
是救生员拉里
It's Larry, the lifeguard
救生员先生  我能摸摸你的肌肉吗
Mr. Lifeguard, can I feel your muscle?
可以
Sure
可别刮花了
Don't scratch the paint
救生员  海浪行不行
Lifeguard, how's the tubage?
太行了
Gnarly, dudes
太好了
All right, yeah
救生员  请问零食吧往哪走
Lifeguard, can you point out the snack bar?
就在那边
Right over there
不过两位长辈年纪太大了
But you guys are way too old
来海滩可能不太雅观
and unsightly for my beach
恐怕得请你们离开了
And I'm afraid I'm going to have to ask you to leave
好礼貌
So polite
真像是我们养大的好孩子
Just like we raised him
好家伙
What a guy
难怪他那么受欢迎
Is it any wonder he's so popular?
想象一下我是个救生员
Just imagine if I were a lifeguard
救生员
那样就太酷了
That would be so cool
你干嘛想当救生员
What do you want to be a lifeguard for?
根本没人喜欢他们
Nobody really likes those guys
因为他是好小子
For he's a jolly, good fellow
当救生员特别傻
Being a lifeguard is so dumb
就只会吹吹吹他们的破哨子
All they do is blow, blow, blow on their stupid whistles
往鼻子涂涂涂那种白色玩意
rub, rub, rub that white stuff on their noses
到处炫耀他们畸形难看的身材
and show off their gross misshapen bodies
兄弟  把那玩意收起来
Dude, put that thing away
海滩有小孩子  看不得这些
There are, like, children here
我要去零食吧
I'm going to the snack bar
谁稀罕当什么救生员
Who needs to be a lifeguard?
我很酷
I'm cool
我从头上下都跟拉里一样酷
I'm every bit as cool as Larry
要是不酷  那我就天打
And if I'm not, let me be struck by
被飞天冰淇淋车砸
A flying ice cream truck
砸不死
and live
请勿把飞天冰淇淋车降落到游客身上
Please, do not land
flying ice cream trucks on the bathers
海绵宝宝  你没事吧
Spongebob, you okay?
我都不知道你是救生员
I didn't know you were a lifeguard
救生员
Lifeguard?
鼻子
The nose
白色玩意
White stuff
你觉得我是救生员吗
You think I'm a lifeguard?
对啊
Sure
救生员的气质是藏不住的  海绵宝宝
there's no hiding the lifeguard look, Spongebob
你就有那气质
and you've got it
你真这么觉得吗
You really think so?
那当然了
You bet, I do
我们这边人手不太够
Say, we're a little shorthanded around here
来海滩这边帮忙怎么样
How would you like to work the beach?
好啊
I'd love it
行
All right
等休息了再来抱吧  海滩大汉
Leave that on the bench, Kahuna
安妮特  过来
Hey, Annette, come here
我要你见见我兄弟  海绵宝宝
I want you to meet my buddy, Spongebob
嗨
Hi
那位是救生员
Guy's a lifeguard
成功了
It works
刚刚最棒了  拉里
That was the greatest, Larry
对啊
Yeah
你要不要等会儿来接我的班
Say, how'd you like to take the second shift?
就我自己
By myself?
你觉得准备好了就接
Only if you think you're ready
我不仅仅准备好了
I'm not just ready
氧化锌膏
还准备好  来哩
I'm Ready Freddie
我叫拉里
It's Larry
那我就
Well, I guess I'll just
救命
Help
有游客落水了
We've got a sinker
海绵宝宝  这个让我来
Spongebob, let me take this
我一整天都还没出动救援呢
I haven't seen any action all day
出动救援
Action?
救命啊
Please, help
给我呼吸啊你
Breathe, darn you
我以后再也不边看书边游泳了
That's the last time I read and swim
你救了我一命
You saved my life
不用客气
Don't mention it
这都是分内的事
It's all part of the job
海绵宝宝你要知道
You know, Spongebob
虽然辣妹和大椅子很棒
the babes and the big chair are great
但是最棒的就是
but the best part is
可以知道只有你才可以
knowing you're the only thing
让海滩上的游客
that stands between these good people
吃吃吃吃吃
Go, go, go, go, go
年度吃热狗大赛
免于溺亡
and a watery grave
这就是救生员的意义所在
And that's what it's all about
他们的命现在交给你了
Their lives are in your hands now
我要去晒日光浴了
'cause I got a date with a tanning booth
再见
See you
可我
But I
不会游泳
can't swim
早知道救生员得救生的话
If I'd known being a lifeguard
meant guarding their lives
我一开始就不会答应
I would never have said yes
也许不会出岔子
Maybe nothing will go wrong
然后等拉里回来
Then when Larry comes back
我再跟他说我不感兴趣
I'll tell him I'm not interested
何况最惨还能惨到哪去
Besides, what's the worst that could happen?
紧急情况
Emergency
全体游客上岸
Everybody out of the water
快
Hurry
紧急情况
Emergency
上岸
Out of the water
紧急情况
Emergency
怎么了  救生员
What's going on, lifeguard?
有什么紧急情况
What's the big emergency?
水里有鲨鱼
There are sharks in there
你是在说我的家人
That's my family you're talking about
有
A
海怪
sea monster
我们海怪极大地促进了
You know, we sea monsters have made great strides
科学与文学领域的发展
in the fields of science and literature
有人尿了
Somebody went?
酷乐湖大得很啊
It's a big lagoon, dude
恶心
Disgusting
不  别走
No, don't go
冰淇淋
免费冰淇淋
Free ice cream
多得很  大家都有份
Plenty for everybody
一份给你  一份给你
One for you, one for you
好  大家都拿到了吗
Okay, everybody got one?
好
Yeah
现在逮到你们了
Now I got you
你们必须得等一小时才能去游泳
Now, you all have to wait one hour
before you go swimming
但为了你们不去冒这个险
But just so you're not tempted
禁止跨越
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen
酷乐湖封湖了
the lagoon is closed
我们更喜欢拉里
We like Larry better
拉里有没有给过你们免费冰淇淋
Does Larry ever give you free ice cream?
港口公厕
冰淇淋
Ice cream
有谁说冰淇淋吗
Did somebody say, "ice cream?"
在哪
Where is it?
禁止跨越
这边吗
Is it here?
冰淇淋
Ice cream
抽筋了
Cramp
我的天啊
Holy cow
有游客溺水了
Somebody's drowning
没那个可能
Oh, no, that's not possible
酷乐湖封湖了
The lagoon is closed
兄弟  快下水去
Dude, get your butt in the water
真要有谁落水  咱肯定能听得到声音
If there was anyone in there, we'd hear them
救命  救命
Help, help
我不会游泳
I can't swim
会有人喊自己溺水了
Somebody would be screaming that they're drowning
我溺水了
I'm drowning
他们得先跨越警戒线
They would have to have crossed the line
我跨越警戒线才溺水的
I'm drowning 'cause I crossed the line
好  我看一眼
Okay, I'll take a look
这样才能向你们证明
but just to prove to you that
派大星没溺水
Patrick isn't drowning
不会游泳
Can't swim
屁股疼
Butt hurts
冰淇淋
Ice cream
坚持住  派大星
Hold on, Patrick
我来了
I'm coming
救命  救命
Help, help
别动
Don't move
抓住这个
Catch this
别胡闹了
Quit fooling around, man
快下水
Get in the water
救命  救命
Help, help
我要怎么办
What am I going to do?
得想想
Got to think
得跑起来想
Got to run around and think
得边跑起来边想
Got to run around and think at the same time
得想想  得有计划
Got to think, got to have a plan
得想想想
Got to think, think, think
有了
I've got it
派大星没水就不会溺水了
Patrick can't drown if there isn't any water
你安全了  派大星
Well, you're safe now, Patrick
救命  我溺水了
Help, I'm drowning
我屁股抽筋
I've got butt cramps
想要冰淇淋  现在天黑了
I want ice cream and now it's dark
救命  救命
Help, help
救命啊  我溺水了
Help me, I'm drowning
救命
Help
敬我们
To us
抱歉
Sorry
热狗还你们
Here's your hot dog
好了派大星  我来了
Okay, Patrick, here I come
快过来  派大星
Come, come 'round Pat
我来了
Here I am
派大星  不要
Pat, Pat, no
等下等下
Hold it, hold it
派大星  住手
Pat, Pat, stop
不  派大星住手
No, Pat, stop
住手  住手
Stop, stop
抱歉
Sorry
救命
Help
救救我  不会游泳
Save me, can't swim
派大星  不要
Patrick, don't
救命
Help
救救我们
Help us
我们溺水了
We're drowning
不知道电影院现在在放什么
I wonder what's showing
at the movie theater right about now
再见了  派大星
Good-bye, Patrick
再见了  冰淇淋
Good-bye, ice cream
救命  不会游泳
Help, can't swim
不要啊
Oh, no
海绵宝宝
Spongebob?
怎么了  拉里
Yes, Larry?
你应该不是救生员吧
You're not a lifeguard, are you?
没错  拉里
No, Larry
我们走吧
Let's go, guys
非常好
Very good
你们学得挺快的
You fellows are learning fast
屁股抽筋了
Butt cramps
我还是没有冰淇淋
And I still don't have my ice cream